你选好地点了吗
So have you picked a place yet?
我很想在植物园办
I'd love to do it at the Botanical Gardens,
但是克里斯觉得那太贵了
but Chris thinks it's too expensive.
这是你的婚礼
It's your wedding.
本来就应该花大钱的
It's supposed to cost a fortune.
我知道  一辈子只能结一次婚
I know. You only get married once.
-我的天  -快打911
- Oh, my god! - Somebody call 9-1-1!
救命啊
Help!
救命啊  救命
Please. Somebody, help! Help!
一会打给你  再见
I'll call you later. Bye.
谁啊
Who was that?
个人隐私  卡塞尔
Personal business, Castle.
真的  是谁啊  好奇心作祟
Really? Who is it? Inquiring minds want to know.
如果你必须要知道  他叫罗杰
Yeah, well, if you must know, his name is Roger.
罗杰
Roger.
别取笑他
Don't make fun.
你知道他有什么没几个人有的东西吗
Do you know what he has that few men have?
乔诗·葛洛班的CD还是洪梅尔陶俑
A Josh Groban cd? Uh, hummel figurines?
不对  风马牛不相及
No, not even close.
罗杰有最不可思议的阻力绳操
Roger has the most incredible Resistance Band.
阻力绳操[阻力乐队]
A resistance band?
那是什么  和我想的一样吗
What is that? Is that what I think it is?
力量训练用的  他是我的物理治疗师
For strength training. He's my physical therapist.
我不知道你还在继续治疗
Oh, I had no idea you were still going.
再继续几周  直到我完全恢复
Yeah, for another few weeks, till I get 100%.
-早上好  -早
- Hey, good morning. - Morning.
什么情况
So what do we got?
死者名叫莎拉·瓦奎斯
Victim's name is Sarah Vasquez.
28岁  是幼儿园老师
She's a 28-year-old kindergarten teacher.
她和同学正离开瑜伽馆
She and a classmate were leaving this yoga studio
莎拉就突然倒下了
when Sarah suddenly dropped.
子弹直射心脏
Bullet wound straight to the heart.
对  但奇怪的是  没人听到枪声
Yeah, what's weird is, no one heard a shot
也没看到枪手
or saw a shooter.
也许武器用了消音设备
Maybe the weapon was silenced.
也许是个流弹
Maybe it was a stray bullet.
刚看过一篇文章
Just read an article,
波特兰的一名邮差如何被
how a mailman in Portland was killed
六个街区外一发对空打出的子弹
When a bullet fired into the air six blocks away
落下时射死的
fell back to earth.
这颗子弹不是从空中落下
This bullet didn't just drop from the sky
射死了莎拉·瓦奎斯
and hit Sarah Vasquez.
角度不对
Angle's wrong.
子弹从她身体由前而后穿过
It went through her from front to back,
不是由上而下
not from up to down.
能确定入射点吗
Can you tell us point of origin?
要做完全尸检才知道
Not until I do a full exam.
莎拉来做瑜伽是固定的吗
Was yoga a regular thing for Sarah?
周二和周四上班前
Tuesdays and Thursdays at 7:00 a.m.,
早上7点来
before school started.
好  查一下有没有仇人
Okay, let's look into enemies
-或者任何知道她在这里的人  -好
- and anyone that knew she was here. - Right.
我们上个月刚刚订婚
We just got engaged last month.
她很兴奋地在筹划婚礼
She was so excited about planning the wedding.
克里斯  谁会有可能想要伤害莎拉吗
Chris, was there anyone that might have wanted to hurt Sarah?
没有
No.
也许是对你们结婚不满的前男友
Maybe an old boyfriend who was upset about the wedding?
她生活中没有那样的人
She didn't have anyone like that in her life.
每个人都喜欢莎拉
Everyone loved Sarah.
等下  昨晚她的确提到了一个男人
Wait. She did mention something last night about a guy.
她认识的人
Someone she knew?
不是
No. Uh...
她说几天前在学校外看到他
She said she saw him a few days ago, outside the school.
然后是周二早上  她说
And then Tuesday morning, she said
她觉得上完瑜伽课的时候又看到他了
she thought she saw him when she got out of yoga.
她有告诉你那人长什么样吗
Did she tell you what he looked like?
我  我不记得了  我
I-I-I can't remember. I...
看来莎拉去瑜伽课的事众所周知
Looks like Sarah's yoga routine was common knowledge.
她甚至把时间公布在了脸谱网上  开玩笑说
She even posted about it on facebook, joked that
就算要她命也要穿上那件婚纱
she was gonna fit into that dress if it killed her.
有人在跟踪她
well, somebody was following her,
我们去和她朋友同事谈谈吧
so let's talk to her friends and coworkers...
看看他们有没有看到陌生男人在附近出现
and see if they saw a strange man hanging around.
马上去
On it.
蕾妮有发现
Lanie's got something.
你们赶紧过来
You should get down here.
杀死莎拉·瓦奎斯的子弹是口径308的
The bullet that killed Sarah Vasquez is a .308,
具体来说是10.9克的赛瑞拉·麦彻金子弹
specifically a 168 grain Sierra Matchking.
来福枪子弹
A rifle bullet.
最喜欢用这种武器的是...
It's a common ammunition favored by...
远程枪手
long-range shooters.
就是说枪手是远距开枪
So she was shot from a distance?
根据她的伤口以及子弹陷入门框的深度
Based on her wound and how deep it went into the door frame,
我估计开枪地点在
I'd say the bullet was fired
180米外到270米外之间
between 200 and 300 yards away.
180米外
200 yards?
能知道确切的开枪地点吗
Do we have any idea where from exactly?
我们还在排查
We're canvassing.
现在只能估计
Near as we can figure...
枪手是在这些楼其中一栋上开的枪
the shooter fired from one of these buildings,
大约在10到15层之间
somewhere between the 10th and 15th floor.
你们  不用为了我刻意避开那个词
You guys, you don't have to avoid the word on my account.
-什么词  -狙击手
- What word? - Sniper.
我都注意到了
Even I noticed.
-我们没在避开  -这是她的主意  她
- We weren't avoiding anything. - It was her idea. She--
听着  我是个大人了
Look, guys, I'm a big girl.
所以我们有话直说吧  这家伙有多厉害
So let's just cut to the chase. How good is this guy?
他不比我队里任何一个枪手  狙击手
Well, he's as good as any of the shooter--snipers
逊色
in my unit.
他射死了四百米开外的移动目标
He took out a moving target from a quarter of a mile away.
她有感觉吗
Did she feel it?
没有  她当场死亡了
No. She died instantly.
那么  我们现在的问题就是
So then I guess the question is,
为什么狙击手要以莎拉为目标
why did our sniper target Sarah?
她提到的跟踪者有线索了吗
Any leads on the guy that she said was following her?
她认识的人没人记得见过这个人
No one in her circle remembers seeing the guy,
除了她未婚夫她没和任何人说过他
and she didn't mention him to anyone but her fiance.
也许跟踪者和这事没关系
Maybe he didn't have anything to do with it.
什么意思
What do you mean?
通常我们找凶手的思路都是了解死者
Well, usually we find our killers by knowing our victims,
找到杀人动机
finding a motive.
但是如果没有动机呢
But what if there isn't one?
如果她只是被随机选中的呢
What if she was shot at random?
那我们怎么找到他呢
How do we find him then?
贝克特中枪了
Beckett's down!
死者是亨利·怀特  律师  38岁
Victim is Henry Wyatt, 38-year-old attorney.
-同一个枪手吗  -看起来是的
- Same shooter? - Looks that way.
有人听到或看到什么吗
Anyone, uh, see or hear anything?
没有  和以前一样  只是这次瞄准了头部
Nada, just like before. He went for the head this time.
他更自信了
He's getting more confident.
同一时间  再度杀人
Another victim, same time of day--
又要上演华府惊魂23天了
This could be the D.C. Sniper all over again.
2002年十月两名丧心病狂的杀手出于对社会的不满
随意狙击杀害十余人  造成社会恐慌
蕾妮  那是子弹吗
Lanie, is that the slug?
对  撞击混凝土时变形了
Yeah, it's all banged up from the concrete,
但看上去口径一致
but it looks like the same caliber.
不过这次射击的角度更大了
The angle of the entry's more extreme, though.
他从更高的地方击中的怀特
He shot Wyatt from higher up.
发现什么了吗
See something?
贝克特  你没事吧
Beckett, you all right?
没事  我只是  只是在想
Yeah, I'm just, uh... I-I'm just trying to figure out
为什么要杀他们两人
why these two victims and--and...
为什么选在这里
why shoot here?
死者可能是随机选择的  但地点不是
The victims might be random, but the location isn't.
职业狙击手会事前侦查他的目标
A pro recons his target beforehand.
如果你要远距离击中目标
If you're gonna kill something from a long distance,
不是瞄准即射而已
it's not a point-and-shoot activity.
你要考虑各种因素  例如目标距离
You factor in all the conditions, like range to target,
角度  还有
minute of arc, and...
风力影响
windage.
怎么了
What is it?
这面旗
This flag...
就是完美的风偏差调整计
is the perfect wind gauge.
这不可能是巧合
That can't be a coincidence.
如果是他挂在这的
Okay, so if he hung that up there,
或许有摄像头拍到他
we might be able to get eyes on him.
我们应彻查这片区域的监控摄像头
We should canvass the area for security cameras--
有一名持枪歹徒
We have a gunman
恐吓着这座城市  一天杀了两人
terrorizing this city-- 2 victims in 24 hours.
我们不知道他是谁  为什么射杀那些人
We don't know who he is or why he shot those folks.
莱恩警探  对两名死者有什么了解
Detective Ryan, what do we know about the second victim?
亨利·怀特是距离被枪杀地点两个街区远的
Henry Wyatt was a litigation partner at a law firm
一家法律事务所的诉讼合伙人
two blocks from where he was shot,
据他秘书所说
and according to his secretary,
他喜欢步行  也就是说他的路线
he liked to walk, which means there was
和莎拉·瓦奎斯的一样可以预测
a predictable routine, just like Sarah Vasquez.
也不能说明凶手就是把他们作为目标
Which doesn't mean they were targeted.
毕竟大多数纽约人的生活都很规律
After all, most New Yorkers follow routines.
埃斯波西托
Esposito...
找到开枪的地点了吗
have we learned where they were shot from?
有小组在排查
We've got teams sweeping...
两个犯罪现场附近的大楼
buildings near both crime scenes,
至今没有发现
and so far, we've come up empty.
我们要找到枪手
We need to find our shooter...
你知道那只是个吃惊反应
You know, it's just a startle response.
可能发生在任何人身上
It could happen to anyone.
可我不是普通人
Yeah, well, I'm not anyone.
-不  我只想说  -别说了
- No, I'm just sayin'. - Just don't.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett...
亨利·怀特和莎拉·瓦奎斯查的怎么样了
where are we on Henry Wyatt and Sarah Vasquez?
你说什么
I'm sorry?
死者之间有什么联系吗
On links between the victims?
我们还在查  但他们不在
We're still checking, but they don't live
同一个地方工作和居住
Or work in the same area,
看上去也没什么共同的朋友
and it doesn't seem like they have anyone in common.
事实上  我们还没发现两名死者之间
In fact, we haven't really found any connections
有任何联系
between the two of them yet.
好的  继续追查
Well, keep looking.
我们知道他具体受过什么样的训练
We know he has training, a specific skill set.
每个军种都有狙击手
Now every branch in the military has snipers...
执法机构也一样
So do law enforcement agencies.
那就是将近
We're talking about close to...
一千名符合条件的枪手
a thousand qualified shooters.
事实是  城里的每一个人都是潜在的目标
The fact is, everyone in this city is a potential target.
快去把他找出来
Let's get it done, people.
等等  你去哪
Wait. Where you going?
我  我有事要做
I-I just have to go do something.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett,
经查证实有监控摄像头
canvass turned up a security camera
正对着挂旗子的地方
across from where the flag was hung.
录像正在往这边传
Footage is on its way in right now.
她没事吧
Is she okay?
不  你不懂
No. You don't understand.
我必须要没事
I need to be okay.
这不总是由你决定  凯特
That's not always a choice, Kate.
你描述的过度警觉  是创伤后应激障碍
What you're describing, a hypervigilance, It's a classic
-一种典型症状  -我没有创伤后应激障碍
- symptom of post-traumatic stress disorder. - I don't have P.T.S.D.
你被狙击手击中了
You were shot by a sniper.
我认为
I think it's fair to say,
这起案子会引发一些问题
this case is going to bring up issues,
-一些你还没处理好的问题  -好吧
- issues you still haven't dealt with. - Okay, then fine.
我会处理好的
I'll deal with them.
现在我需要想办法让这一切停下来
Right now I need to figure out how to make this stop.
不会就这么停止
It's not going to stop,
这需要时间和治疗
not without time and treatment.
心理创伤就和生理创伤
The psychological trauma is every bit as real
一样真实
as the physical trauma.
听着  外面有人死去
Listen, people are dying out there.
我没空为几个伤疤哭哭啼啼的
I don't have time to get all weepy over a couple of scars.
好吧  那你不去处理会怎样呢
Okay. So what's the alternative,
时刻觉得有把枪正瞄准着你
walking around feeling like you have crosshairs on your back,
觉得每扇窗户的反光就是狙击手的镜片
thinking every glint off a window is a sniper's scope?
总有药之类的能治  对吧
Look, there's gotta be a pill out there or something, right?
能缓解我的紧张情绪
Something to take the edge off.
药物治疗会起作用
Medication can help...
-但也不是即时的  -那该怎么办
- but not right away. - Well, then what?
目前而言
Well, for one,
我认为你应该考虑退出这个案子
I think you should consider stepping away from the case.
你认为我处理不了吗
You don't think I can handle this?
我是说
I'm saying...
你不必逞强
You don't have to.
你不是城市中唯一的警察  凯特
You're not the only cop in the city, Kate.
好吧
Okay.
你知道吗
Then you know what?
我没事了
I'm fine.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我是不是应该很替贝克特担忧呢
How worried should I be about Beckett?
她以前从没这么对我发火
She's never snapped at me like that before.
而且是真发火了
And meant it.
我从前线回来的时候也不好受
Hell, it was bad for me when I came back,
可我从没吃过子弹
and I never took a bullet.
至少她不记得了
Well, at least she doesn't remember it.
她也可能不想记得
Or she doesn't want to remember.
发生这样的事  尘封在心底反而更容易
A thing like that, it's easier to just keep in a box.
可这宗案子可能又唤醒了记忆
But this case might bust that box open.
那我们能做什么
So what can we do?
-抓住枪手  -他说得对
- Catch the shooter. - He's right.
这对大家都好  也包括贝克特
Best thing for everyone, Beckett included.
与此同时  给她点空间
In the meantime, just give her space
别觉得她是针对你
and don't take it personally.
伙计们  来看这里
Hey, guys, check this out.
这是在两天前下午四点半
This is 2 days ago at 4:30 p.m.
他挂上那面旗  他肯定就是枪手
He planted the flag. He's gotta be our shooter.
他知道摄像头的位置
He knows where the camera is.
所以他的脸避开了摄像头
That's why he keeps his face covered.
为什么选这条街
Why choose this street?
为什么不选个没有监控摄像头的地方
Why not pick a place without any security cameras?
因为他这是在故意挑衅
'cause he's straight up taunting us.
我去让死者的同事和朋友认人
I'll run this photo by victims' coworkers and friends,
看看有没有人认识他
See if anyone recognizes him.
他不会这么轻易就让我们逮住  是吧
He is not gonna make it easy for us to catch him, is he?
是  他聪明而又耐心
No. He's smart and he's patient.
那是狙击手必备的素质
that's part of a sniper's D.N.A.
喂
Yeah.
别进去
Don't go in.
去叫鉴证组  我十分钟后到
Call C.S.U. I'll be there in ten.
警员刚找到了狙击手射杀亨利·怀特的地方
Uniform just found where the sniper shot Henry Wyatt from.
对了
Yep.
这里就是犯罪现场
There's the crime scene.
五百五十米
600 yards.
世界级的射击水准
World-class shot.
-可完全不对劲   -什么意思
- But it's all wrong. - What do you mean?
狙击视野部分被那棵树挡住了
The view of the kill zone is partially obstructed by that tree.
楼顶的视野更佳
A better shot would've been from the roof.
凶手应该知道这点
Our boy would know that.
那他为什么选这里呢
So why wouldn't he take the shot from up there?
他可能是怕被其它更高的大楼
It's possible he was worried about being seen
或路过的直升机上的人看到
by someone in a taller building or a passing helicopter.
那是什么
What's that?
小纸人
A paper doll.
可能是狙击手留下的吗
Think maybe it was left by the sniper?
或者
Or...
是工人的孩子留下的
One of the workmen's kids.
狙击是在这扇窗前开枪的吗
So the sniper took the shot from this window.
不
No.
他应该不想让街上的人注意到他
He would've wanted to be invisible from the street.
所以会选择
He'd have taken the shot from...
这里
right here.
他慢慢地
He took his time...
瞄准那根旗帜
to spot that flag.
根据风速矫正瞄准
Adjusted for wind.
看到目标
Acquired his target.
嘣
Bam.
弹壳
The shell casing.
会被弹到右边
It would've ejected to the right.
抱歉
Sorry.
你去哪里了  我打过电话给你
Hey. Where have you been? I called you.
我手机没电了  什么事
uh, yeah, my phone's off. What's--what's up?
狙击手杀死怀特的藏身处发现的弹壳上有指纹
Shell casing from the Wyatt sniper hide had a print on it.
我们刚匹配到一个前特种部队狙击手
We just matched it to a former special forces sniper
名叫马库斯·福特
named Marcus Ford.
刚经历了惨痛的离婚
Just went through a bitter divorce--
典型的暴力发作导火索
Textbook trigger for that kind of violence.
福特在长岛经营一家射击场
Ford runs a shooting range in Long Island.
州警派了战术小组
State police have a tactical team
正赶去和我们会合
on the way to meet us there now.
要不
Uh, maybe, uh,
我们就留在这里吧
it would be a good idea if we hung back here?
我们会调查福特  准备对他进行审讯
We'll study up on Ford, just prep for the interrogation.
好  那也不错  我们搞得定
Yeah, that's a good idea. We got it covered.
好
Yeah, okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们的警察在你的射击场里
Our officers found a whole arsenal
发现了不少武器  福特先生
at your shooting range, Mr. Ford.
据我所知
Last time I checked,
我还有权持有枪支
I still have the right to bear arms.
对  你该知道弹道小组
Yeah, well, you should know that ballistics
在检查你的来福枪
is testing your rifles.
查吧  我没开枪杀人
Have at it. I didn't shoot anyone.
不是如此吧
Well, that's not exactly true, is it?
根据你的军事记录
According to your military record,
-你杀死过92个人  -那又怎样
- you have 92 confirmed kills. - So?
你想破百吗
You lookin' to make it an even hundred?
透过瞄准镜  定夺他人生死
What's it like to look through the scope,
感觉如何
to play god?
当你扣下扳机  毁人性命的时候
How do you feel when you pull that trigger
感觉如何
and you destroy someone's life?
感觉就是这不关你的事
It's none of your damn business is how it feels.
知道我怎么想吗
You know what I think?
我觉得你该站到枪口前
I think that you should be on the other side of that barrel.
这是威胁我吗  你在威胁我吗
Is that a threat? Are you threatening me?
那些人是什么  他们只是你的纸靶子吗
What are those people? Are they just paper targets to you?
你有想过你带来的痛苦
Do you even think about the pain that you've caused,
和留下的残缺家庭吗
about the families that you leave behind?
我杀的每个人都是为了救一个自己人
Every life I ever took saved one of ours!
说的跟真的似的  知道我怎么想的吗
Like hell it did! You know what I think?
我觉得你乐在其中
I think that you liked it.
觉得你等不及再大开杀戒
I think that you couldn't wait to kill again.
你疯了  女士
You're outta your mind, lady.
我们在凶手留下的弹壳上发现了你的指纹
We found your print on a shell casing left by the sniper.
不可能
That's impossible.
你撒谎
That is a lie.
我没什么好说的
I have nothing left to say.
我有权保持沉默
I know my rights.
福特的武器都没匹配上
Ne of Ford's weapons are a match.
所以呢  那也不能说明他就不是凶手
So? That doesn't mean he's not the sniper.
他可能把枪给藏起来了
He could've hidden the rifle.
福特不是凶手
Ford's not our man.
两起枪击案中他的不在场证明都被证实了
His alibis for both shootings are solid.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我想我知道怎样确认不在场证明  探长
I think I know how to check an alibi, detective.
如果他不是我们要找的凶手
Well, if he's not our man,
那他的指纹怎么会出现在子弹壳上
How the hell did his fingerprint get on that shell casing?
可能是重填的子弹
Could be a reload.
往我们找到的那种空子弹壳里
It's easy enough to load a new bullet
重填火药是件挺容易的事儿
into an empty shell casing like the one we found.
只要有相应设备就能搞定
All you need is the right equipment.
这就是说  我么要找的狙击手
Which means our sniper
是福特射击场的客户
is a client at Ford's shooting range.
回去询问室请他协助调查
Go back in there and get his help.
经过刚才你这么讯问
He's not gonna want to talk to us
估计他不会愿意配合我们调查了
after the way you went after him.
你是想说  我搞砸了吗
So what are you trying to say, that I screwed up?
不是
No, um--
我想他的意思是
I think what he's saying is that
你扮演了坏警察的角色
You played bad cop.
如果我进去扮演好警察的话
And now we'll get more out of Ford
我们能从福特口中得到更多信息
if I go in and play good cop.
好的  就这样吧
Okay, fine.
或许福特可以帮助我们抓到凶手
Maybe Ford can get us what we need to nail this guy.
福特先生  关于之前我很抱歉
Mr. Ford, my apologies.
有枪
Gun!
凯特
Kate!
喝点咖啡不
Coffee?
不用了  多谢
No. No, thanks.
这是无咖啡因的  听我说
It's decaf. Look...
卡塞尔  我没事
Castle, I'm fine.
-我知道  但是  -我说真的
-Right, but... - No, really.
我没事  文件夹里是什么
I'm fine. What's in the folder?
鉴证组关于小纸人的鉴证报告
C.S.U. report on the paper doll.
这不是小孩子剪出来的
This was not made by a kid.
是用美工刀  非常精准地裁出来的
It was cut out very precisely with an x-acto knife.
从哪里裁  杂志吗
Out of what, a magazine?
不是  这个纸质很厚
No, the paper stock is too heavy,
而且考虑到背面没有印东西
and given there's nothing printed on the back,
可能是从什么高级案头书之类的上裁下来的
it's probably from some high-end coffee table book of some kind.
我猜是  油画画册
My guess-- a book of paintings.
如果你仔细观察  可以看到画笔的笔触
If you look closely, you can see brush strokes.
应该是狙击手故意留下的
I think the sniper left that.
他为什么这么做
Why would he do that?
原因我就不清楚了
That much I don't know.
马库斯·福特帮不上什么忙
Marcus Ford was no help.
他无法确认录像中的人是谁
He couldn't I.D. the guy in the video.
我们准备追查他的信用卡收款记录
We're pulling his credit card receipts,
但他说射击场上大部分交易都是用的现金
but he says that the shooting range is mostly a cash business.
在哪儿
Where?
好的  我们马上到
Okay. We're on our way.
莱恩找到了狙击手射杀莎拉·瓦奎斯的大楼了
Ryan found the building the sniper shot Sarah Vasquez from.
管理员认出了照片里的那件夹克
The super recognized the jacket from the photo,
说他之前经常在那幢楼附近出没
said he'd been hanging around the building.
如何确认是这间房间
How do we know he was in this room?
因为我们又找到了一张小纸人
Because we found another one of these.
就是这里  他正是在这儿开枪杀了莎拉·瓦奎斯
This is it. He shot Sarah Vasquez from right here.
这与我们找到的第一个不太一样
This is different from the first one.
肯定是从另一幅画上裁下来的
It must be from a different painting.
它们一定有什么特别的意义
They've gotta mean something.
比如什么  它们会有什么特别的意义
Yeah, like what? What's it possibly gonna mean?
我也不知道  但是他肯定是有意留下的
I don't know, but he's leaving 'em for a reason.
是的  他在玩弄我们
Yeah, he's screwing with us.
嘲笑我们  那我们当猴耍
He's just taunting us and trying to make us look like idiots.
我们会查出来的  别急躁
We'll figure it out, okay?
我找到点东西
Found something.
软毛皮
Moleskin.
老练的狙击手把它
Hard-core military snipers put it
垫在枪的托手上来吸汗
on the stocks of their weapons to absorb sweat
这样子枪才不会打滑
So their rifles don't slip.
如果上面有汗水  那就能查到DNA
If there's sweat, we can get D.N.A.
是的
Yeah.
快去查
All right, go.
这里就是一切开始的地方
This is where it all started.
就在这间屋子里  他扣动扳机
He pulled that trigger right in this room.
前一秒钟  莎拉·瓦奎斯还活着
One second, Sarah Vasquez is alive
还在幻想她的完美婚礼
and dreaming of the perfect wedding,
后一秒钟  她就死了
And then she isn't.
凯特
Kate...
你知道吗  他在开枪时看到了她的脸
You know he saw her face when he killed her?
人们都以为
People always think
狙击手离目标很远
that snipers are so removed from their targets.
但并非如此  从瞄准镜里看
But he wasn't. He is as close as we are right now,
他就像你我现在这么近
looking through that scope.
我们会抓到凶手的
We're gonna catch this guy.
是啊  就像我们抓到那个向我开枪的人
Yeah. Like we caught the guy that shot me.
亲爱的
Oh, darling.
你不会熬了一整夜吧
I hope you haven't been up all night.
我睡不着
Ah, I couldn't sleep.
两天里死了两个人
Two days, two people dead--
有个人  刚刚醒来
Someone out there is waking up
完全不知自己将成为第三个被害人
not knowing they're gonna be murder number three.
我忽然决定  我今天还是逃学吧
I think I just decided to skip school today.
事实上  我认为你们俩都该被软禁
Actually, I think you're both under house arrest
直到我们抓住凶手为止
until we catch this guy.
我能想象这个狙击手
Oh, I can only imagine how this sniper
肯定让贝克特心烦意乱
must be affecting Beckett.
她说她没事
She says she's fine...
那你打算怎么做
So what are you gonna do?
现在我唯一能做的
The only thing I can do--
就是查出他留下这些小纸人的原因
try to figure out why he's leaving these damn dolls behind.
如果能弄明白他们是从什么画上裁下来的就好了
If I could just figure out what painting they're from.
让我看看
Let me see.
明暗对比法
Chiaroscuro.
你认识吗
You recognize that?
这是文艺复兴时期兴起的一种画风
It's a style of painting that was invented during the renaissance,
特点在于突显明暗反差
exemplified by strong contrast between light and dark.
艺术史课上学到过
We learned about it in art history.
卡拉瓦乔  意大利画家
佩特扎诺  卡拉瓦乔当学徒时的工作室
你可以查查卡拉瓦乔
Try looking up Caravaggio
或者佩特扎诺
or Petrazano.
我能不能感叹一句  给你付
Can I just say, this school of yours
那么多学费真是物有所值
is worth every penny I paid?
可能是这个
Hey, this might be it.
佩特扎诺
Petrazano.
"国王的迫害"
"The Persecution of Kings."
在软毛皮上找到的DNA没用
DNA on the moleskin was a bust.
莱恩  有结果了吗
Ryan, you got results?
在系统里没找到能与之匹配的
There were no matches in the CODIS database.
实验室最多能根据基因表型做出推测
The best the lab was able to do was DNA phenotype,
他们认为狙击手
and they say they think our sniper
为男性  浅色头发  棕色眼睛
is a male with light hair and brown eyes,
但我们仍有200余名嫌疑犯符合此描述
but that still leaves us with over 200 suspects on our list.
现在还不能缩小名单范围
I wouldn't cut down the list yet.
根据我们的弹道检验结果
Given what we went through with the shell casing,
那软毛皮可能根本不是他的
there's a chance the moleskin's not even his.
我知道那个小纸人是什么意思了
I know what the paper dolls mean.
卡塞尔先生  现在不是你戏剧演出的时候
Mr. Castle, now is not the time for your theatrics.
警监  你听我说  这个小纸人是有预言性的
Captain, just listen. The paper dolls are predictive.
纸人是从画上剪下的
The dolls are cut out of paintings
而从这些画可以断定下一个目标地点
that literally tell us the location of the next target.
我们在第一个枪击案现场发现的小纸人
The one that we found at the first shooting,
是从一副叫做"国王的迫害"的画上剪下的
it comes from a painting called "The Persecution of Kings."
亨利·怀特是在国王街被杀的
Henry Wyatt was killed on King Street.
正是
Exactly.
在第二次狙击地点发现的纸人
The one we found in the hide of the second shooting,
出自"失去恩典"那幅画
that's from a painting called "The Fall from Grace."
布朗克斯区有一条恩典大道
There's a Grace Avenue in the Bronx.
恩典教堂在第10街和第四大道的交口处
Grace Church is on... 10th street and 4th avenue.
有十几种可能
And there's about a dozen other possibilities.
如果我们能缩小范围
If we can narrow it down...
也许我们就可以阻止他...
we might be able to stop him before he...
恩典
Grace.
有多少人死亡
How many people are dead?
-没有  -谢天谢地
- None. - Thank god.
狙击手透过窗户
Yeah, sniper opened fire
向十五楼的会议室开火
through the window of a conference room, on the 15th floor.
有其他人受伤吗
Is anyone else injured?
只有她一个
No, just her.
她叫艾米丽·瑞斯  他只射中了她
Her name is Emily Reese, and he only shot at her.
艾米丽  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Emily, my name is Detective Kate Beckett.
我要你告诉我当时发生了什么
I need you to tell me what happened.
为什么是我
Why me?
我做了什么
What did I do?
为什么会有人想杀我
Why is somebody trying to kill me.
艾米丽  最近有人跟踪你吗
Emily, have you seen anybody watching you lately?
没有  我不知道
No. I-I don't know.
-我们得送她去医院  -不行
- We gotta get her to the hospital. - No!
别把我送出去
Don't let them take me outside.
他还在外面
He's still out there.
你会没事的  艾米丽
No, you're gonna be okay, Emily.
别这么做  他就在外面
Please don't do this. He's out there.
他会杀了我的  求求你
He's going to kill me. Please.
快走  送她离开这里  快
Just go. Get her outta here. Now. Go.
求你了  不要
Please. Please, no!
凯特
Kate.
她无法控制自己
She's spinning out of control.
她根本无法应对
She's losing her ability to cope.
不应该让她接这个案子
She should not be on this case.
你知道她不会就这么走开的
Well, she's not just gonna walk away.
没错  她会被这案子拖进泥潭的
No, she's gonna drive herself into the ground.
而你是唯一能理解她
And you're the only one who has any clue
所处境地的人
as to what she's going through.
当时你是怎样走出来的
So what helped you?
埃斯波  我们在这里做什么
Espo, what are we doing back here?
我要给你看点东西
I want to show you something.
这是什么
What is that?
射伤你的那把来福枪
The rifle that shot you.
你做的太过了
You are way outta line.
看看它
Just look at it.
你到底在干什么
No. What the hell are you doing?
我也经历过
I've been where you are.
我明白你现在的挣扎
I know what you're going through.
哈维  我很好
Javi, I'm fine.
你不好
You're not fine.
你只是假装安然无恙
You're just trying to act like you are.
这不过是个工具
This is just a tool.
无非是一堆钢铁
It's a hunk of steel.
它并非魔力万丈
It has no magical powers,
举着它发射子弹的人
and the person that fired it
也不是什么全能真主
is not some all-powerful god.
他不过是持了枪
He's just a guy... with a gun,
就像我们正在追捕的这个人一样
just like the guy we're hunting now.
跟其他坏人一样  都是内心有创伤的人
And like every other bad guy, he's damaged goods.
我也是啊
So am I.
没错
That's right.
那没关系
And that's okay.
你觉得这是弱点
You think it's a weakness?
让它成为你的优势
Make it a strength.
这是你的一部分
It's a part of you.
好好利用它
So use it.
查到狙击手为何选艾米丽·瑞斯做目标吗
Any idea why the sniper targeted Emily Reese?
还没  她是电信公司的副总裁
Not yet. She was a V.P. at a telecom company,
单身  刚买了西96街的一套公寓
Single, just bought an apartment on west 96th.
没查到和其他被害人有任何关系
No known connections to the other vics.
但他在跟踪她  这是肯定的
But we do know he was following her.
卡塞尔  有何发现
Castle, what do you have?
这是艾米丽所在大楼的监控录像
You're looking at a video taken from Emily's lobby
昨天下午一点四十
yesterday at 1:40.
也就是他射杀怀特后四小时
That's four hours after he shot Wyatt.
这是艾米丽  正走进电梯
There's Emily, getting into the elevator.
他在那
There he is.
他就是我们要找的人
That's our guy.
是的  但很不幸  我们还是看不见他的脸
Yeah. Unfortunately, we still can't see his face.
他站在那干嘛呢
What is he waiting for?
他等着看她在哪层工作
He's watching to see what floor she'd get off on.
他清楚地知道她要去哪里
He knew exactly where she was gonna be.
艾米丽没死真是个奇迹
It's a miracle Emily's not dead.
这可不是奇迹
It's not a miracle.
只是计划不周详
It's poor planning.
我们的狙击手用错了弹药
Turns out our sniper used the wrong ammo.
168型子弹一旦穿过玻璃就会丧失稳定
The 1-6-8 grain loses stability when it goes through glass.
165型子弹才是那种射杀的绝佳选择
The 1-6-5 is designed for that kinda shot.
他不了解
He didn't know that,
说明他根本不像我们想得那么专业
which means he has less experience than we thought.
现在我们重新查看嫌疑人名单
Okay, we need to go back to the suspect list,
排除所有执法部门的狙击手
cross off all law enforcement shooters
和在城市工作的部队老兵
and any combat vets with urban experience.
是我看错了
Is it just me...
还是他的咖啡杯和艾米丽的一样
or is his coffee cup identical to Emily's?
一样的标志
Same logo.
来自同一家店
It's from the same shop.
放大点看看
Zoom in on that.
普利莫咖啡馆
Caffe... Primo.
他肯定是从那里开始跟踪她的
Must have followed her from there.
如果他是那的顾客  也许会有人认得他
I-if he's a customer, maybe someone can I.D. him.
只有一家普利莫咖啡馆  在47街
There's only one Caffe Primo. It's on 47th Street,
离艾米丽工作的恩典大厦就两个街区
2 blocks from the Grace Point Tower where Emily worked.
我们得查查
Okay, we need to find out
看其他被害人是否也是那家店的顾客
if any of the other victims have a connection to that shop.
好的
All right.
贝克特在哪
Uh, where's Beckett?
她在追查一条线索
She's running down a lead.
从房顶射击  角度更好
Why would you shoot from here
为何你要选择在此射击
when the roof gave you a cleaner shot?
那间咖啡店有可能是关键
That coffee shop may be the key.
莎拉·瓦奎斯的家离恩典大厦六个街区
Sarah Vasquez lived six blocks from the Grace Point Tower.
她钱包里有张三天前去
And she had a receipt in her wallet from Caffe Primo
普利莫咖啡馆消费的小票
from Caffe Primo dated three days ago.
亨利·怀特呢
What about Henry Wyatt?
怀特治疗师的办公室
Wyatt's therapist has an office
刚好在咖啡馆的那条街上
right across the street from the coffee shop.
在被杀的两天前  他去过那治疗
He had a session two days before he was killed.
那家店就是他选择目标的地方
That shop's gotta be ground zero where he selected his victims.
马上去那  给我确定凶手身份
Get the hell down there and get me an I.D.
时间紧迫  他就要对下一个被害人下手了
The clock's ticking on his next victim.
对  他们都是这的常客
Yeah, they all get coffee here on a pretty regular basis.
你是说杀手射杀我店里的客人
Are you saying he shoots people from my shop?
可能只是个巧合
It could be just a coincidence.
他们是不是一起来过
Have any of them been in here together?
一起聊过天或是跟他人聊过
Maybe talking to each other or anyone else for that matter.
我记得没有过
Not that I remember.
那这个男的你认识吗
What about this guy?
他也是这的顾客吗
Is he a customer?
他就是狙击手吗
Is that the sniper?
你见过他吗
Have you seen him?
他看起来眼熟吗
Does he look familiar?
不认识
No.
抱歉  如果我能看见他脸的话  也许
Sorry. Maybe if I could get a better look at his face--
罗伯特  去接电话
Robert, phone call.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我希望我能被录取
I'm just praying that I get accepted.
你爸也是那毕业的
Your dad's an alumni.
你肯定会被录取的
You're in for sure.
兄弟  成交了
Yo, dude. I totally closed the deal.
八位数合同还有附带产品
Eight figures and a piece of the merchandising.
不不  兄弟  太赞了
No, it was epic, bro.
你能去后面
Hey, can you go in the back
再拿点咖啡伴侣出来吗
and get some more of that, uh, creamer?
我可不愿接受  这里任何一个人的死
I hate to think that any of these people are dead
只是因为他们没选对买咖啡的地方
just because they picked the wrong place to buy coffee.
跟咖啡馆无关
It's not the coffee shop.
我知道被害人有什么共同点了
I know how the victims are connected.
是什么
How?
莎拉·瓦奎斯刚刚订婚
Sarah Vasquez just got engaged,
亨利·怀特成为了他事务所的合伙人
Henry Wyatt just made partner at his firm...
艾米丽·瑞斯刚在上西区
And Emily Reese just bought a giant apartment
买了套顶级公寓
on the upper west side.
他们近来都喜事不断
They all had recent successes.
根据我们的侧写
According to our profile,
狙击手是个偏执的自闭者
this sniper is a paranoid loner.
他感觉自己被世界孤立了
He feels alienated,
被世界伤害了
victimized by the world.
他进这家店买了杯咖啡
He comes into here for a cup of coffee,
听见每个人诉述着自己幸福的人生
and he hears about how well everyone's doing,
梦想如何实现
how their dreams are coming true.
他的挫败
While his are not
让他感觉自己被忽视
makes him feel invisible,
令他气愤至极
makes him feel angry.
所以他选择其中之一下手
So he picks one of them out,
让他们付出代价
and he makes them pay.
即使你是正确的
But even if you're right, it doesn't get us
对我们抓住这家伙也没什么帮助
it doesn't get us any closer to catching this guy.
如果我们问对了问题就能
It might if we ask the right question.
他没有选择从房顶射击
He didn't shoot from the roof
是因为他爬不了那么高的楼梯
because he couldn't climb the ladder.
如果你细心看录像
If you look at the video,
会发现他走路略显蹒跚
there's a slight hitch in his step.
我推测他腿部有点残疾
I think he has a physical disability.
罗伯特
Uh, Robert.
你能想起
Does this ring a bell
谁是瘸子或是腿有伤吗
a guy with a limp or a leg injury?
最近几周
There is a homeless guy
有个流浪汉常来这里
who's been hanging around the last few weeks.
我想他是装的义肢
I think he's got a prosthetic leg.
我们需要你描述他的长相
We're gonna need a description.
在名单中输入残疾
All right, adding disability
全部或部分截肢
and partial and/or full amputation to the list,
嫌疑人从207个
cuts it down from 207...
锐减到三个
to three.
-艾瑞克·霍华德  李·特维斯  -就是他
- Erik Howard, Lee Travis... - That's him.
李·特维斯
Lee Travis.
38岁
He's 38 years old.
在一起肇事逃逸的摩托车事故中失去右腿前
He did a year in the marines before losing his right leg
他在海军服役过一年
in a hit-and-run motorcycle accident.
一直没抓到肇事者
Never caught the driver of the car,
而李则被迫光荣退伍了
and Lee was given an honorable discharge.
他心理咨询师的报告中指出
And according to his counselor,
李在那场意外后患上了重度抑郁症
Lee went into a deep depression.
他把他的愤怒转嫁给了整个世界
Turned his anger against the world.
他干过很多底层工作  其中包括
He did a string of low-paying jobs, including a stint
在大都会艺术博物馆当保安
as a security guard for the Metropolitan Museum of Art,
他的老板说他当时经常长时间地泡在
where his former boss said he spent a lot of time
大师著作区
in the old masters section,
他正是在那里接触到的卡拉瓦乔和佩特扎诺
home of Caravaggio and Petrazano.
我这就把李的照片和他的特征通报给媒体
All right, I'm releasing Lee's photo and bio to the media.
用不了多久
Within the hour,
纽约市的所有人都会认识他
every person in New York will know who he is.
等一下  长官  你确定那是个好主意吗
Wait, sir. Are you sure that's a good idea?
如果他知道我们正在逼近他
If he knows that we're closing in,
那可能会引发他再次大开杀戒
that might trigger another shooting.
我们必须冒这个险
We need to risk it.
一旦我们把他的样貌公布于众
We put his face out there,
就会有人注意到他  并向我们报告他的去向
it could give us a lead on his whereabouts.
我们对他的家人了解多少
What do we know about his family?
李有个姐姐住在皇后区
Lee has a sister in Queens.
埃斯波西托在找她
Esposito's tracking her down right now.
你确定是他吗
Are you sure it's him?
是的
Yes.
你并不惊讶
You're not surprised.
李是个心怀愤怒的人
Lee's an angry guy.
自从那场意外后  他就一直很愤怒
He has been since the accident.
我已经尽力去帮他了  可是
I tried to do what I could, but...
如果对方不接受你的帮助  你也没办法
You can't give help if someone won't take it.
他干出这种事  太让我伤心了
It breaks my heart that he would do something like this.
你最后一次见他是什么时候
When was the last time you saw him?
大约一个月前
About a month ago.
他那天来皇后区找我
He came out to Queens for the day.
可结果却不欢而散
It didn't go well.
他的公寓被收回了
He lost his apartment,
他想搬到我家来住  但是
wanted me to ask him to move in with us, but...
我不想让他接近我的孩子们
I didn't want him around the kids.
你知道他住在哪吗
Do you know where he's living?
他走的时候  我把我的旧车给他了
I gave him my old car when he left.
是辆蓝色的顺风达斯特
It's a blue Plymouth Duster.
你还能把车牌号写下来吗
Do you think you could write down the license plate number?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
在哪
Where?
我们马上来
We're on our way.
抱歉  我们得走了
I'm sorry. We gotta go.
巡警刚刚找到了
Uniforms just found the third hide
他射伤艾米丽·瑞斯时的藏匿点
where Emily Reese was shot from.
警探
Detective.
我知道我弟弟干了坏事  但是
I know my brother's done terrible things, but...
求求你们别伤害他
please don't hurt him.
他是怎么找到这些地方的
How is he finding these places?
就跟他选择目标一样  他偷听别人的谈话
The same way he chooses his victims. He listens.
他是个流浪汉  没人会留意他
He's homeless, so nobody notices him.
他一旦找到合适的大楼
Once he finds a building that he'll be shooting from,
他就开始侦察地形  找到最适合射击的地点
he recons it for the best vantage point.
卡塞尔
Castle...
我们必须找到那个小纸人
We need to find that paper doll,
查出他下一次行凶的地点
see where he's gonna strike next.
找到了
Found it.
天啊
Oh, my god.
能确认下一位被害人的身份吗
Does it I.D the next victim?
不是一个
Not victim.
而是多个
Victims.
一名巡警找到了李的车
A patrol unit found Lee's car.
在车尾箱里发现了这些
These were in the trunk.
-找到枪了吗  -没有
- Any sign of the gun?  - No.
好吧
All right.
大家听好了  我要所有人进入战术警戒状态
Listen up. I want all units on tactical alert.
李·特维斯正带着他的武器在城里游荡
Lee Travis is out there right now with his weapon,
意图杀害他的下一批被害人
intending to kill multiple victims.
考虑到前三位都是在早上被射杀或射伤
And given that the first three were shot in the morning,
我们的时间不多了
we don't have a lot of time.
我找到了
I got it!
你知道他那串纸人是从哪里剪出来的了吗
You know where he cut the chain of dolls from?
我早些时候说服他们让我进博物馆里调查
I convinced them to let me into the museum early.
我把这些纸人
I compared the dolls
跟博物馆的收藏品进行了一一比对
to all the paintings in their collection.
这幅画叫做"草地上的雄狮"
It's called "Lions in the Meadow".
纽约市里的唯一一片草地是在
The only meadow I know of in New York is at...
是在中央公园
is in Central Park.
我们应该假设特维斯现在已经就位了
We should assume that Travis is already in position.
如果我们现在疏散游客  他会马上开始射击
If we start clearing the park, he might start firing.
不管这些被害人是谁  他选择他们的理由
Whoever these dozen victims are, he's targeting them
跟他选择前三名被害人的理由是相同的
for the same reason he went after the others,
所有我们可以假定他们来自于同一个群体
so we can assume they're all part of the same group.
贝克特  带上所有人手  马上赶往中心公园
Beckett, take everyone we can spare, head for the park.
一旦我们琢磨出结果
I want you in place and ready to move
我希望你迅速行动
when we figure this out.
莱恩  马上打电话给公园管理部门
Ryan, get on the phone to the parks department.
看看他们今天早上有什么活动安排
Find out what they have scheduled there this morning.
卡赛尔  你来不来
Castle, you coming?
我在这能帮上更多忙  我要帮莱恩
I'm more useful here, helping Ryan
搞清楚他的目标是谁
figure out who the targets are.
你自己去没问题的
You got this.
这些树冠会使他很难
All that tree cover is gonna make it hard for him to target
瞄准公园内的任何区域
any large area of the park.
而且公园东西两面的大楼都是
Also, the buildings on the east and west sides of the park
配有守门人的高级公寓楼
are high-end apartments with doormen.
也就是说他必须从
Which means he would have to shoot
公园南面找射击地点
from the south end of the park.
我刚跟公园管理部门通过话
I just got off the phone with the parks department.
中央公园今天有十多项活动
There's over a dozen events planned in Central Park today.
公园南面有什么活动吗
Anything on the south end?
一个自然保护区参观  和一个
A nature sanctuary tour and a...
西部高中的庆典活动
celebration for Western High School.
他们学校的田径队刚刚拿了州冠军
Their track team just won the state championship.
他们现在应该正在去公园的路上
They should be on their way into the park right now.
等等  西部高中离那家咖啡店只有
Wait. Western High School's three blocks away
三个街区的距离  他们的田径队就叫雄狮队
from the coffee shop. Their team's called the Lions.
李肯定是听到了某个学生或是某个学生的家长
Lee must have heard one of the parents or students
大谈他们的胜利
boasting about winning that meet.
他们怎么去公园
How are they getting to the park?
坐校车
Coming in by bus.
我马上联系应急小组
I'll call E.S.U.
莱恩  我们得停下那辆校车
Ryan, we need to stop that bus.
听着  学校有辆巴士
Listen, the school has a bus unloading
在公园的大将军广场入口停车  学生下车
at the Grand Army Plaza entrance at the park.
应急小组告诉盖茨这两栋楼
E.S.U. told Gates that these two buildings
对狙击手来说有最好的射击位置
have the best vantage point for the sniper.
应急小组的反狙击人员什么时候能到
How long till E.S.U. countersnipers get here?
10分钟后  大家排查20楼以上的每一层楼
10 minutes, so search all of the floors above the 20th.
行动
Let's go.
接电话啊
Come on. Come on.
赶紧接电话  该死
Answer your phone, damn it!
发现有扇门开着
I got an open door.
2421房间  我进去了
Suite 24-21. I'm going in.
住手  警察
Stop! Police!
放下枪  李
Put the gun down, Lee.
我有活儿要干
I have a job to do.
我看你还是直说吧
why don't you just call it what it is, okay?
你那是冷血地射杀无辜市民
You shoot people in cold blood.
那些人该死
Those people deserve what they're getting.
上帝保佑了他们
God blessed them.
他恩宠了他们  却忽略了我
He gave to them and took from me--
我的腿  我的生活
My leg, my life.
那有多么地不公平
How is that fair, huh?
那样对吗
How is that right?
那些你怨恨的人  他们跟你一样
Those people that you blame? They're no different from you.
你这么说不过是因为你跟他们一样
You're just saying that 'cause you're one of 'em.
你以为我的生活很美好吗
You think my life is a picnic?
我知道被别人瞄准是什么感觉
I know what if feels like to be in those crosshairs,
知道子弹穿过胸膛是什么感觉
To feel the bullet burn through my chest.
我知道濒死的时候是什么感觉
I know what it feels like to have my life leave my body.
我认为你也知道
And I think you do, too.
所以你才会一直留下那些小纸人
That's why you keep leaving those paper dolls behind,
因为你在寻找能有个人
because you're looking for somebody
来帮你找到其他办法
to help you find another way.
没有其他的办法
There is no other way.
-不再有了  -不
- Not anymore. - No.
-太迟了  -不不
- It's too late. - No, no.
总有办法的
There's always another way.
我想帮助你  我知道你很痛苦
I want to help you. I know that you're in pain,
我们能找到更好的办法让别人知道你的痛苦
and we can find a better voice for your pain.
-求你放下枪  -转过去
- Please just put that gun down. - Just turn around.
-不  -别看着我  转过去
- No. - Don't look at me. Just turn around.
-不  -转过去
- No! - Turn around!
不  如果你要射杀我
No. If you're gonna shoot me,
你就直视我的眼睛
You look at me in the eyes, okay?
你看清楚
And you look hard,
因为我不是你的敌人  那是不可能的
because I am not your enemy. I can't be.
你我有太多共同点了
You and I have too much in common.
不  我们没有
No, we don't.
我有活儿要干
I have a job to do.
抱歉了
Sorry.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
等我的搭档
Just waiting for my partner.
也许你见到她了
Maybe you've seen her.
漂亮姑娘
Pretty girl,
认为她能一跳越过摩天大厦
thinks she can leap tall buildings in a single bound,
能将世界的重量扛在自己肩上  然而呢
carries the weight of the world on her shoulders, yet...
还是能被我的些许笑话逗乐
still manages to laugh at some of my jokes.
听起来她这人很难相处啊
She sounds like a handful.
可不是嘛
Tell me about it.
总之呢
Anyway...
如果你见到她
If you do see her,
告诉她  她欠我大概一百杯咖啡
tell her she owes me about a hundred coffees.
卡塞尔
Castle.
谢谢
Thank you.
为什么谢我
For what?
没有给我压力
For not pushing
给我空间  让我去跨过这道坎
and giving me the space to get through this.
应该的
Always.
李·特维斯死了  你感觉如何
So how do you feel now that Lee Travis is dead?
我以为抓到他会解决问题
I thought that taking him down would resolve things,
但是...问题依旧存在
But... it's still there.
因为你还没有全身心地去应对你的遭遇
Because you haven't fully dealt with what happened to you.
不是
No.
被射伤之前就有这种感觉
I felt it before the shooting.
我认为它一直在那
I think it's always been there,
那晚之后  它就藏在内心深处
Deep inside, since that night.
你妈妈被谋杀那晚
The night your mom was killed.
是啊
Mm-hmm.
那件事界定我了  驱使着我
I've let it define me, drive me.
使我成为了现在这个样子
It's made me who I am.
但现在
But now...
继续说
But now?
我想要进一步
I want to be more
去发掘自己
than who I am.
但我不知道在不让我妈妈失望的前提下
But I don't know if I know how to do that
我能不能做到
without letting my mom down.
她死了  凯特
She's dead, Kate.
你不会让她失望
You can't let her down.
你只会让自己失望
The only person you can let down is yourself.
她的死成了你的一部分
Her death is a part of you.
你要想办法去释怀
And you're gonna have to make peace with that,
就像你不得不去释怀
Just like you're gonna have to make peace
那被射伤的伤口
with the scars from your shooting.
但那不应该限定你
But it doesn't have to limit you.
我怎样才能放手
How am I supposed to let go?
我能帮助你
I can help you.
但问题是
But the question is,
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
我想我准备好了
Yeah, I think I am.